Tareq Aghabi

+971 (52) 522 9094 | taregaghabi@gmail.com | LinkedIn

PROFILE

Senior Data Analyst and Industrial Engineer with 4+ years of experience in Supply Chain Digitization, Advanced Analytics, Data Modeling, Business Intelligence Development, and Tech Logistics, proficient in SQL, LookML, Google BigQuery, PowerBI, Python, R, JavaScript, HTML, ERP Dynamics 365, and Excel. Canadian and Jordanian citizen, native in English and Arabic.

EDUCATION

Georgia Tech University, School of Computational Science and Engineering

Atlanta, GA

Master of Science in Analytics (MSc)

January 2023 - Present

Relevant Coursework: Data Science, Machine Learning, ETL, Object-Oriented Programming, Web Development, Cloud

International Federation of Purchasing and Supply Management IFPSM,

Dubai, UAE

Certified Advanced Supply Chain Professional (CASP)

November 2022

Relevant Coursework: Cost Analysis, Planning, Forecasting, Sourcing, Warehousing, Inventory Management, Logistics

Harvard University, School of Engineering and Applied Sciences

Professional Certificate in Data Science (PCert)

February 2021

Relevant Coursework: SQL, Python, R, Visualization, Probability, Wrangling, Regression, Machine Learning & AI

Concordia University, School of Engineering and Computer Science

Montréal, QC

Bachelor of Science in Industrial Engineering (BEng)

May 2019

Relevant Coursework: Operations Research, Stochastic Models, Simulation, Calculus, Probability & Statistics

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Chalhoub Group - Largest luxury goods retailer and distributor in MENA

Dubai, UAE

Data Analyst II - Supply Chain Central Team - Managed Companies Management

January 2022 – Present

- Worked alongside the Chief Demand and Supply Planning Officer as part of the Central Supply Chain Management and drove the Group's upstream and downstream strategic direction by establishing executive, management, and operational reporting and prescriptive analysis on eight global retail and distribution business entities of over 500 unique brands.
- Modeled and coded over thirty KPIs and Looker BI dashboards used by executive-level management to track inventory, service levels, weekly trade, sell-in sell-out, vendor & supplier performance, and e-comm supply chain. Improving standardized visibility by 100% and delivering actionable insights to key stakeholders.
- Engineered, simulated, and merged 10TB of supply chain data using Google BigQuery and SQL, standardizing product grading on a global, country, and brand level and automating the root cause analysis on fill rate and on-shelf availability.
- Governed Supply Chain KPIs and Dashboards as a data steward, authorizing over 200 LookML data merges from the wider supply chain data analyst community, maintaining supply chain data governance to 100%.
- Optimized query performance using LookML aggregate tables, decreasing query cost by 20TB, increasing dashboard speed, and improving user experience.
- Organized and hosted two offsites for supply chain leaders, senior managers, and data analysts on supply chain KPI alignment and organized a dashboard-building competition in which I built the highest-ranking dashboard with a performance score of over 100%.

Goodfood Market Corporation - Canada-wide online grocery delivery

Montréal, OC

Operations Analyst – Big Data Analytics & Supply Chain Operations

August 2020 - January 2022

- Promoted to Operations Analyst within eight months for exceeding goals and supporting company culture.
- Configured the weekly system changeover for over 1500 new SKU items in the Goodfood E-commerce backend database and ERP warehouse management system, determining multi-facility SKU picking & storage locations and inventory replenishment triggers based on analysis of order volume projections and operations cost analysis.
- Automated customer order data pull schedules from Looker into Google Sheets to develop an interfacility inventory replenishment analysis model using JavaScript, improving item replenishment availability and visibility by 50%.
- Strategically assigned over 3000 multi-facility SKU storage and picked location data into the Goodfood E-commerce backend database and ERP warehouse management system using Microsoft SQL Server Studio queries.
- Created over ten automated analysis tools and visualization dashboards for logging short ship data, managing labor cost, and tracking shipping carrier progress, providing daily item management decisions to senior directors and executives.

<u>United Parcel Service</u> (UPS) – Global shipping & logistics

Montréal, QC

Industrial Engineering Specialist – Route Optimization Engineering Project Team

April 2019 - May 2020

- Utilized proprietary mapping and optimization software to plot and schedule delivery route information for over 70 training and verification rides on deployed driver groups, decreasing route delivery mileage by 15%.
- Extracted and manipulated route-specific statistics stored in UPS proprietary databases using Excel Visual Basic to generate over 25 technical reports, providing corporate-wide visibility to overall project deployment progress.
- Optimized and scheduled over 1800 driver and helper meetups in all regions of Montréal and Laval using UPS logistics software, resulting in an increase of 70 stops per package car during peak season.
- Created a Master Operating Plan for the Data Acquisition department documenting the data collection and transformation methods for package processing at UPS, standardizing data processing operations and decreasing errors by 25%.